Arghya Bandyopadhyay

3127, Sector 23, 2nd Floor • Gurugram, India • 122017 • Mobile No. 7224077631 • EMAIL arghyab13bga@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I am a curious and passionate developer. Been a Software engineer at NatWest Group for 5 Months and a Full Stack Developer with 2 years' of professional experience in terms of freelancing and an extensive range of skills including Java and Flutter. I can develop efficient micro services using SOLID techniques. I have also developed web apps and SPAs using Angular. I love optimising the codes and making them efficient. I have been writing codes using Java since when I was in class 9 and have a very thorough hold on the language. I also work on open source projects and believe that all the codes written by me shouldn't be rewritten.

PROFILE

LinkedIn, Github.

EDUCATION

2020-2022 | Master of Technology (9.29)

From National Institute of Technology Durgapur, West Bengal, India

2016-2020 | Bachelor of Technology (8.72)

From Shri Shankaracharya Group of Institutions, Bhilai, Chhattisgarh, India

2014-2016 | Class 10+2 (91.6%)

From O.P. Jindal School, Raigarh, Chhattisgarh, India

SKILLS

Java, Spring Boot, Flutter, Database, Node.js, AngularJs, Express.js, Micro services, Full Stack Development, Game Theory.

EXPERIENCE

Jul 2022 – Current | NatWest Group **Software Engineer**

Responsibilities: Design and develop reusable libraries and application programming interfaces for use across the bank. Design and develop software that is amenable for a greater automation of build, release testing and deployment process on all environments. Support the reuse and sharing of platform components and technologies within the software engineering teams. Deliver software components to enable the delivery of platforms, applications and services. Write unit and integration tests, in automated test environments to ensure code quality.

May 2020 - Jul 2022 | Self-Employed Freelance Full Stack Developer

Responsibilities: Pixel-perfect implementation of our approved user interface. Design and deployment of our database and REST API. Integrating our front-end UI with the constructed API. Development of Mobile Applications for Android and IOS. And Integration of applications with Firebase.

Sep 2020 – May 2022 | National Institute Of Technology, Durgapur

Teaching Assistant

Responsibilities: Carrying out research work on game theoretic model formulation of kidney exchange program for Indian medical space. Assisting the conduction of lab classes on Advanced Data Structure and Algorithms.

Feb 2020 – Mar 2020 | Anvy Technologies Full Stack Developer (Internship) **Responsibilities**: Make the projects using Java(JavaFx), Laravel(Php, Ajax, Javascript, Jquery). Conduct software analysis, programming, testing and debugging. Ensuring the quality of code and deliverable is high.

Jul 2018 – Sep 2018 | Vedas Technocrats Java Developer (Internship)

Responsibilities: Make the projects using JavaFX. Conduct software analysis, programming, testing and debugging. Ensuring the quality of code and deliverable is high.

RESEARCH

March 2021 – May 2022 | Kidney Exchange problem(Game Theory)

I worked on how to adapt to the kidney exchange problem in India. What are the problems faced in kidney exchange and what can be solutions. This problem is categorised under mechanism design.

PROJECTS

Sept 2022 – Oct 2022 | Money and **Monetary(Spring Boot, Angular)**

The prime objective of the project was to develop a fund transfer system, in which the user, when opt for round ups, would be deducted by a certain amount in every transaction and would be added to a savings account. This is an initiative to increase savings. In this project, I developed a rest-api using spring boot based on micro service architecture, and the front end using angular.

June 2021 – Current | Open source ERP(Javafx, Css)

I started this project as an initiative to create an ERP which is open source. There are very few free, open source ERPs running in the market.

Jan 2021 – Dec 2021 | Fee management and Video lecture streaming application(Flutter)

The project is basically intended for Gym owners/trainers and also for zumba classes. The application enables the users to keep a track of the payment dates, dues and other payment related stuff. And also paid video lectures.

May 2020 - Nov 2021 | An Mobile **Application Module for an ERP (Flutter)**

The application is intended for the owners out of station or town, but need to get

updates of their business. The app is much more than the update with features like order punchings, invoice generation and many others.

Mar 2020 - Nov 2020 | Online Customer Order Punching Application (Flutter)

Started with a vision of an application which is used in restaurants, by the waiters to punch orders and eventually also allow the customers to punch the orders by themselves. Now it is being adapted for other verticals too.

Feb 2020 - Mar 2020 | Inventory **Management Application (Laravel)**

This was a website developed for a gold warehouse in order to manage its inventory and to assign inventory goods to the workers. There were basically two intended users for the website, the admin and the agents.

Feb 2020 – Mar 2020 | Billing Software for a Tailoring Shop (JavaFx)

A normal billing and pseudo accounting software for a tailor shop. The entire project was made using JavaFX.

Sep 2019 – Apr 2020 | Student Attendance System Using Face Recognition (Python)

A student's attendance system working on a face recognition system using opency. There was a feature of assignments being shown based on the face recognition. It also has a bulk message sending feature.

Oct 2015 - Dec 2015 | Digital India Software (Java Swing)

The Software was intended to issue documents for people, it was just an idea converted into an application. The Languages used were Java and Sql.

Oct 2015 – Dec 2015 | Java Quiz (Java

KBC type Quiz Developed in Java.